dolby.com 2016-03-17

# Dolby Privacy Policy

_Effective January 26, 2016_

In this Website Privacy Statement ("Statement"), we, Dolby Laboratories, Inc., provide information about how we collect, use, and transfer personally identifiable data from you, a visitor to our www.dolby.com website and all associated sites offered by and/or linked to www.dolby.com and on which we post a direct link to this Statement (collectively the "Site").

## Scope

This Statement covers only data collected through the Site and not any other data collection or processing, including, without limitation, data collection practices of other web pages to which we link or data that we or our affiliates collect offline or through websites that do not display a direct link to this Statement. Occasionally, we may refer to this Statement in notices and consent requests related to surveys, contests, and special-purpose web pages; under such circumstances, this Statement applies as modified in the particular notice or consent request (e.g., with respect to types of data collected or purposes of collection).

Some of our business units and web pages apply this Statement subject to specifically disclosed modifications, supplements, or exceptions.

## Types of Data and Collection Methods

Through the Site, we receive data that you actively submit as well as data that we track:

_Actively Submitted Data:_ When you sign up to receive certain types of information, such as email newsletters, product software upgrades, and some licensee-related documents, or otherwise actively send us data, such as to participate in a contest or engage with a website we operate for business partners (such as our voice partner network) you are providing, and we collect, data such as your name, email address(es), mailing address(es), telephone number(s), login credentials, business details, and any other information you provide. In each such instance, you will know what data we collect through the Site, because you actively submit it.

_Passively Tracked Data:_ When you visit the Site, we also passively track information on your computer and Internet connection, such as the IP address of your computer and/or Internet service provider, the date and time you access our websites, the Internet address of websites from which you link to our Site, the computer technology you are using, and your movements and preferences on our Site. We use technology that many other websites employ, including, without limitation, "cookies" or small data files stored on your computer's hard drive, to collect information such as the aforementioned. In some instances, we also use cookies to collect information in connection with future visits from that Site, to recognize you as a previous visitor and to track your activity on the Site. You do not need to have cookies turned on to visit our Site. You can refuse cookies by turning them off on your browser.

_Combinations:_ Unless you also actively submit personal information such as your name or address, passively tracked data may allow us to identify a business, but does not typically allow us to identify individuals personally (even though it can theoretically be done, we do not have the means or an interest to find out who an individual website visitor is, unless you identify yourself voluntarily through an active submission of data). To the extent permitted by applicable law, we reserve the right to combine passively tracked data with personal data that you actively submit.

_Analytics:_ We may use third-party analytics services on our Sites, such as those of Google Analytics. The analytics providers that administer these services use technologies such as cookies to help us analyze your use of the Site and your demographics and interests. To learn how to opt out of Google Analytics, please [click here](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout "click here"). 

## Collection Purposes, Use of Data

We collect passively tracked data primarily for purposes of administering, protecting, and improving our Site and our systems, to better understand the preferences of our Site visitors and participants in contests and other special events, to identify server problems, to compile aggregated statistics about Site usage, and to help personalize your experience of our Site.

We collect actively submitted data primarily for a few purposes: for the purpose for which you originally sent us the data (e.g., to mail information to you or facilitate your use of a website created for business partners), for internal use as research data to improve our products and services, to facilitate participation in contests and other special events, and for purposes of informing you about products and services or otherwise communicating with you; you can opt out of receiving marketing emails as explained below.

## Data Transfers

We may transfer the personal information we obtain about you to countries outside of the country in which the information originally was obtained. Those countries may not have the same data protection laws as the country in which you initially provided the information. When we transfer your information to other countries, we will protect that information as described in this Statement.

If you are located in the European Economic Area ("EEA") or Switzerland, we will comply with applicable legal requirements providing adequate protection for the transfer of personal information to recipients in countries outside of the EEA or Switzerland.

## Disclosures of Personal Information

We are not in the business of selling or renting your information to telemarketers and do not share your personally identifiable information with others, except as follows:

  * We freely share your information with our affiliates.
  * We also share your information with agents and service providers who are required to use the data only on our behalf and for our purposes under confidentiality agreements.
  * We may share your information as required by law or in the interest of protecting or exercising our or others' legal rights, e.g., without limitation, in connection with requests from law enforcement officials and in connection with court proceedings.
  * We may share or transfer your information in connection with a prospective or actual sale, merger, transfer, or other reorganization of all or parts of our business.
  * Also, we reserve the right to fully use and disclose any information collected via the Site that is not in personally identifiable form.

## Your Rights and Choices

_Opt Out:_ In connection with promotions, contests, or other projects, we may ask you specifically whether you have objections against a certain kind of data use or sharing. If you opt out under such circumstances, we will respect your decision. To opt out of receiving further commercial emails or to unsubscribe from services, please contact us at unsubscribe (at) dolby.com. Please note that other data recipients have their own data privacy policies, which may differ from ours, and you would have to contact them separately with respect to opt-out requests.

_Access:_ To the extent provided by the law of your jurisdiction, you may request access to the personal information we maintain about you or request that we correct, amend, delete or block the information by sending us an email.

_Do Not Track:_ We currently do not respond to "Do Not Track" signals.

## Security

We maintain administrative, technical, and physical safeguards designed to protect the personal information you provide against accidental, unlawful, or unauthorized destruction, loss, alteration, access, disclosure, or use. It is your responsibility to safeguard any password and User ID you use to access the Site, and you are solely responsible for any unauthorized use of the Site conducted via your password and User ID.

## Children's Privacy

The Site is intended for adults in the United States. We do not intentionally or knowingly collect personally identifiable information from children under the age of 13, and we request that individuals under the age of 13 not submit any personal information on the Site.

## Effective Date, Amendments

This Statement is effective as of the date noted above. We reserve the right to change this Statement from time to time and at our sole discretion. We reserve the right to change, modify, add, or remove portions of this Statement at any time, but will alert you that changes have been made by indicating on the Statement the date it was last updated. When you visit the Site, you are accepting the current version of this Statement as posted on the Site at that time. We recommend that users revisit this Statement on occasion to learn of any changes.

## Contact Us

Please feel free to send us an email to exercise your rights or if you any comments, questions, complaints, or suggestions you might have regarding the information practices described in this Statement. You also may write to privacy (at) dolby.com, or to:

Dolby Laboratories, Inc.  
Attn: Privacy - Legal  
1275 Market Street  
San Francisco, CA 94103-1410 USA

Residents of the European Union may write to:

Dolby Europe Limited  
Attn: Legal EMEA  
4-6 Soho Square  
London W1D 3PZ  
United Kingdom
